Contact

mohibayub23@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/mohibayub-009a33147 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills & Technologies

Deep Learning

Natural Language Processing

Blockchain

Data Visualization

Problem Solving

Python (Programming Language)

Courses / Certifications:

Data Visualization

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign · Coursera

Machine Learning

Stanford University · Coursera

Software Engineering Virtual Experience JPMorgan Chase & Co. InsideSherpa

Organizational / Volunteering Experience:

Logistics Assistant

inGenious hackathon, 2019

IEEE PESIT South Campus Student Branch volunteer

Registrations Assistant

ICACCI Conference, 2018

Founding Board Member

ACM PESU-ECC Student Chapter

Mohammad Mohib Ayub

Summary

Experienced Founding Board Member of ACM Student Chapter with a demonstrated history of working in the Educational Technology and Computer Software industry. Mentorship experience in AI and Machine Learning workshops and development of Deep Learning and Neural Network models.

Brief knowledge about Software Verification and Validation with an experience in automated testing with Selenium.

Skilled in Python (Programming Language), Computer Science, Machine Learning, Linux, and Algorithms. Strong business development professional with a Bachelor of Engineering focused in Computer Science.

Education

PES University Electronic City Campus (Affiliated to VTU)

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Science · (2017 - 2021)

Experience

UniConverge Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

Machine Learning Intern

April 2020

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Deep Learning Model Development for Natural Language Processing Tasks

Qin1 · CodeQ

Online Instructor (Internship)

March 2020 - April 2020

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Technology Teaching Department

Techwarts

Student Mentor

October 2018 - October 2019

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Mentorship at Machine Learning club.

Bolt IoT

Student Intern

April 2019 - May 2019

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Business Development and popularizing concepts of ML & IoT.

Other activities, Hackathons and Competitions:

Game Jam 2018, game development hackathon at PES University.

dotSlash 2019, open innovation challenge at PES University.

Kludge 2019, PES University Electronic City Campus.

IoT Congress India 2019, PoP91 innovation challenge by IET India.

Projects

1. IoT based prediction of forest fires · April 2019:

The prototype planned to build is a real-time prediction and alert system based on environmental sensors that uses classification techniques to predict occurrences of fires and protects forest assets and prevents fires from spreading.

2. Detection of illegal deforestation & logging with Neural Networks · August 2019:

Detection of illegal logging by Audio Processing with Convolutional Neural Networks over protected forest regions. The prototype planned to build is a system which could detect sounds of logging trucks, chainsaws, hammers etc. and detect suspicious activities in the vicinity of a protected region.

3. Human Activity Recognition using Smartphones · October 2019:

Human Activity Recognition (HAR) is classifying activity of a person using responsive sensors that are affected from human movement. Both users and capabilities (sensors) of smartphones increase and users usually carry their smartphone with them. These facts make HAR more important and popular. This work focuses on recognition of human activity using smartphone sensors using different machine learning classification approaches. Data retrieved from smart phones' accelerometer and gyroscope sensors are classified in order to recognize human activity.

4. Driver Drowsiness Detection · March 2020:

The objective of this project is to build a drowsiness detection prototype that uses Python, OpenCV, and Keras which will alert the driver when he feels sleepy. The trained model will detect that a person's eyes are closed for a few seconds. This system will alert the driver when drowsiness is detected.

5. Retrieval-based Chatbot · March 2020:

The chatbot prototype is built using deep learning techniques. The chatbot will be trained on the dataset which contains categories (intents), pattern and responses. We use a special recurrent neural network (LSTM) to classify which category the user's message belongs to and then a random response from the list of responses is given.

The chatbot is a retrieval based chatbot which uses NLTK (Natural Language Processing Toolkit), Keras and is programmed in python.

6. Multilingual Toxic Comment Classification · April 2020:

It only takes one toxic comment to sour an online discussion. A main area of focus is Machine Learning models that can identify toxicity in online conversations, where toxicity is defined as anything rude, disrespectful or otherwise likely to make someone leave a discussion. To identify these toxic contributions and to achieve a safer, more collaborative internet, we make use of a Graphical Generative BERT model in Keras (tensorflow 2.0) with HuggingFace transformers Python library, providing pre-trained models that are extraordinarily useful for Natural Language Processing (NLP).